So for more complicated metrics, you might need to estimate the variance
所以针对更为复杂的指标 你可能需要通过实证
empirically instead of computing it analytically.
预测方差 而不是通过分析计算
Are there any other reasons to use the empirical method?
还有什么其他原因让我们选择实证方法么？
>> So, fundamentally what you're doing when you're computing
基本上 你在计算指标方差的时候
the variance of a metric,
你需要对数据潜在的分布
is you're making an assumption about the underlying distribution of the data.
有一个假设
For a relatively simple metric, making that assumption makes total sense and
对相对简单的指标来说 给出一个假设是很合理的
you should absolutely do that, but
你绝对应该这么做
as you get to more complicated metrics, the distribution can be very weird and
但对于比较复杂的指标 分布可能会很奇怪
that's why you might want to shift to an empirical estimate.
这就是为什么你需要转用实证估计
Now, at Google, what we found was that even for some of the simple metrics,
现在在 Google 甚至在一些简单的指标中
the analytical estimate of the variance ended up being an underestimate.
我们也会发现方差的分析估计最后还是出现低估的情况
And we were actually very surprised by that, and
我们感到很吃惊
we'll actually explain some of the reasoning as to why it turns
在第四课中 我们会解释为什么
out that it's an underestimate more in lesson four.
会出现低估的情况
But because of that, we shifted to using A versus A experiments across
但是 因为这种情况 我们开始全面使用 A/A 实验
the board to estimate the empirical variability of all of our metrics.
从而通过实证预估所有指标的差异性
>> What are A versus A experiments again?
能再说明以下什么是 A/A 实验么？
>> So this class is about A/B testing, where you have control,
我们这课是关于 A/B 测试的 你有对照组
your A, versus your experiment, the B.
A 对比实验组 B
And any changes that you measure between A and
如果 A 和 B 之间测量出什么变化
B are due to the changes in the system that you've done.
那是因为你在系统中进行的变更
Now in an A versus A test, what you have is a control, A against another control
而在 A/A 测试中 你有一个对照组 A 对比另外一个对照组 A
A, and so there's actually no change in what the users are seeing.
实际上用户看到的东西是没有什么改变的
What that means that any differences that you measure are due to
也就是说你测量到的任何区别都是因为
the underlying variability, maybe of your system,
潜在的差异性 比如说你的用户群体系统
of the user population, what users are doing, all of those types of things.
用户的行为 等等等等
Now I think Carrie mentioned how we might use A versus A experiments
Carrie 之前提及过 我们要如何使用 A/A 实验
to actually test for the sensitivity and robustness of metrics.
实际测试指标的敏感性和合理性
For example, if you see a lot of variability in a metric in an A versus
比如说 如果你在 A/A 测试中发现指标的差异性很大
A test, it's probably too sensitive to be useful in,
可能在使用它评估真正的实验时
in evaluating a real experiment.
它的敏感性会太高
>> Okay.
好的
So you can kind of pin down the variability with these A/A tests.
所以你可以使用 A/A 测试确定差异性
How many do you usually need to get a good sense?
那要得到合理的判断的话 你需要进行多少测试？
>> Well, at Google we started with ten, then we moved to twenty.
在 Google 一开始我们使用十次 后来是二十次
Now, we literally run hundreds of A versus A tests
现在我们会运行数百次 A/A 测试
at a whole bunch of different sizes.
规模各有不同
Now, clearly there's a diminishing return as you run more A versus A tests.
你运行更多的 A/A 测试的话会有明显的边际效益递减
The key rule of thumb to keep in mind is that the standard deviation
要记住 一个很关键的经验法则就是
is going to be proportional to the square root of the number of sample.
标准偏差与样本量的平方根成正比
>> That's great if you have enough traffic and you run your own experiments
当然 如果你有足够的流量 能够运行自己的实验 这当然很好
so that you can run that many, but what if you can't for some reason?
你可以运行很多实验 但如果由于某些原因 你不能做到呢？
>> Well, another option is to run one really big A versus A experiment.
那另外一个选择就是做一个规模很大的 A/A 实验
And then there's a method in statistics called the bootstrap, where what you do
然后统计学中有种方法叫 bootstrap (自助法)
is you take that big sample, and you randomly divvy it up into a bunch of
你可以将很多的样本随机地划分为一堆小样本群
small samples and you do the comparison within those random subsets.
然后可以对这些随机的子集进行对比
I think you're going to basically be explained that technique more
我们会在下一章中更具体地
in the next section.
解释这项技术
>> Yeah, so why wouldn't you always use the bootstrap method so
那为什么你不长期使用 bootstrap
that you wouldn't need to run that many A/A tests?
这样就不需要运行这么多的 A/A 测试了？
>> It's definitely an option.
这个肯定是个选择问题
One advantage of running the several, many, or
运行很多不同的 A/A 测试的其中一个好处是
just lots of different A versus A tests is because if your experiment system
如果你的实验体系本身很复杂
is itself complicated, it's actually a very good test of your system.
它能帮助你测试你的系统
So, for example, is your randomization function truly random?
比如说 你的随机功能是否真的是随机的？
Do you have any other issues with regards to bias or
你是否有偏差或者
weird population effects?
奇怪的群体效应之类的问题？
Or anything else along those lines,
或其它这些方面的问题
you can actually truly test that with the A versus A tests.
你可以通过 A/A 测试真正地测试这些
Now, in reality, what we have is a whole gradation of different methods.
而在现实中 我们有各种不同等级的方法
If you're starting out and you're running your first experiment using
如果你准备使用相对简单的指标 开始运行你的第一次实验
a relatively simple metric, do the analytical estimate of your ants.
你可以进行分析估计
As you're starting to push towards more complicated metrics or
如果你准备使用比较复杂的指标
you're running more and more features through,
开始运行更多的功能
at that point, you might want to consider at least doing the bootstrap.
这个时候 你至少要考虑采用 bootstrap
Now if your bootstrap estimate is agreeing with your analytical estimate,
如果你的 bootstrap 估计与分析估计结果一致
you can probably move on and you don't have to worry about it.
那可能你就能继续下一步 不需要担心
But if your bootstrap estimate isn't agreeing with your analytical,
但如果 bootstrap 估计与分析估计结果不一致
at that point you may want to consider running a lot of A versus A tests and
这个时候 你可能就需要考虑运行大量的 A/A 测试
really digging into understanding what's going on.
深入了解发生了什么情况